Randolph W. and Beatrice H. Whaples Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Randolph W. and Beatrice H. Whaples Papers.
undated, 1923-1957.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Whaples, Randolph W.
Whaples, Beatrice Child Healey
2 linear feet.
Randolph W. Whaples and Beatrice C. H. Whaples graduated from Connecticut Agricultural College in 1927. Mrs. Whaples returned to the University of Connecticut in the mid 1950s and was awarded an M.S. degree in 1957. The collection contains course notes, assignments, papers, quizzes, examinations and similar materials related to the academic career of the Whaples.
MSS19890049
Biography
Randolph W. Whaples was born in Newington, Connecticut in 1902 and attended New Britain High School. He and his wife, Beatrice C. H. Whaples, graduated from Connecticut Agricultural College in 1927. After graduation, Whaples was employed as New London County's first full-time 4-H Club agent. In 1935, he took a similar post in Hartford County. From 1948 until 1959, Mr. Whaples administered the University of Connecticut Cooperative Extension Service for 4-H youth programs as state 4-H leader. During World War II, he was farm labor supervisor in Hartford County in charge of recruiting personnel for wartime farm labor. From 1944 through 1946, Whaples was the area representative for the United States Department of Agriculture War Food Administration program in New England and later New York. After his retirement in 1959, he became a rural youth leader for the Agency for International Development Program in Ceylon. He also helped establish 4-H programs in Iran, Taiwan, and the Philippines. He was also a youth advisor in Uganda.
A long-time resident of Mansfield, Mr. Whaples was a deacon at the Storrs Congregational Church and a member of the Mansfield Planning and Zoning Commission. He died at home at the age of 72 in 1974.
Mrs. Whaples returned to the University of Connecticut in the mid 1950s and was awarded an M.S. degree in 1957.
Scope and Content
The collection contains course notes, assignments, papers, quizzes, examinations and similar materials related to the academic career of both Mr. and Mrs. Whaples.
Arrangement
Series I: Connecticut Agricultural College coursework ( 1923-1927 ) contains coursework, notes, examinations and experiment reports pertaining to the academic courses of Randolph Whaples and Beatrice Healey.
Series II: University of Connecticut coursework ( undated, 1956-1957 ) contains coursework and notes from Mrs. Whaples graduate courses.
Series III: Personal Papers ( undated ) includes notes, correspondence and personal materials.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history. See especially, the University Memorabilia Collection and other student related collections. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
The name Arthur Lorentzon appears in one of the notebooks. It appears that Mr. Lorentzon was a classmate of Mr. Whaples. Mr. Lorentzon has also donated a scrapbook to the Memorabilia Collection.
Separated Material
Materials that have been separated from the collection and integrated into the main Memorabilia Collection include: Dance cards, student fee statments, Junior Week programs, and similar. All have been identified with the MSS number for this accession.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Whaples, Randolph W.; Whaples, Beatrice Child Healey
Organizations:
Connecticut Agricultural College.; University of Connecticut.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Notes.; Sketches.; Examinations.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Mrs. Whaples donated the materials in 1989.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Connecticut Agricultural College coursework, 1923-1927
  - Agronomy, 1923 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Animal Husbandry, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Animal Husbandry/Botany, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - [Apiculture/Horticulture/Pomology?], undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Art Appreciation, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Botany I, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Botany, 1924 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Chemistry, undated (Box 2:, Folder 8)
  - Dairy Husbandry, 1924 (Box 2:, Folder 9)
  - Economics 3, 1925 (Box 2:, Folder 10)
  - English, undated (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Entomology, undated (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Experiment notes, 1926 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Experiments, undated (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Fashion (Clothing Design), undated (Box 3:, Folder 15)
  - Forestry, undated (Box 3:, Folder 16)
  - History/Chemistry II, undated (Box 3:, Folder 17)
  - Horticulture, undated (Box 3:, Folder 18-19)
  - Mechanic Arts, 1923 (Box 3:, Folder 20)
  - Military Science, undated (Box 3:, Folder 21)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - Orchard Spraying, undated (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - Papers and notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 24)
  - Plans, undated (Box 3:, Folder 25)
  - Textile Lab, undated (Box 3:, Folder 26)
  - Textiles, undated (Box 4:, Folder 27)
  - Zoology I, undated (Box 4:, Folder 28)
  - Zoology IV, undated (Box 4:, Folder 29)
- Series II: University of Connecticut coursework, undated, 1956-1957
  - Foods and Nutrition 250, 1956 (Box 4:, Folder 30)
  - Home Economics Education, 1957 (Box 4:, Folder 31)
- Series III: Personal Papers, undated
  - Personal Papers, undated (Box 4:, Folder 32)